<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide - Warsaw</string>
    <string name="city_info">WARSAW</string>
    <string name="art_info">ART IN WARSAW</string>
    <string name="history_info">HISTORY</string>
    <string name="food_info">WHAT TO EAT!</string>

    <string name="city01">The City - The name appears in the 14th century as Warseuiensis (1321), Varschewia (1342) and XV century as Warschouia (1482). The medieval name was Warszewo, Warszowa. It most probably comes from the lease form of the name of Warsaw (abbreviated form of popular Old Polish name Warcislaw, Wrocisl), used among others. By the representatives of the Rawa family of Rawa, the owners of parts of the area in the area of ​​contemporary Solc and Mariensztat. Probably Warsaw from the Rawa family received a prince in the 13th century, from which a village bearing his name was born. Changing its name to Warsaw resulted from the Mazovian dialectical pronunciation. By the end of the 15th century, the vowel-a-was in soft-consonant echoes (-that was a soft consonant at the time). In the fifteenth century, the molds of the secondary e-began to be seen as a noise. Therefore, it was replaced with -e by -a. Such a change was not etymologically justified, so such forms are called hyper-legal (eg, sit, kings). This was also the case with the change of name from Warszewo to Warsaw, which became popular in the 16th century. Legendary etymology derives its name from the names of Wars and his wife Sawy.</string>
    <string name="city02">Central Park - It was founded in 1932 on the initiative of the Society of Friends of Żoliborz in the area of the former Russian fortifications from the 19th century (Fort Sergey Citadel of Warsaw Sokolnicki). An artillery fort is a central part of the park. The designers of the park created in modernist style were Leon Danielewicz and Stanisław Zadora-Życieński. On the square, just behind the main entrance from pl. Wilson, set up fountain sculpture Alina - girl with pitcher chisel Henry Kuny. Surrounded by round lawn and spruce trees. The whole park is cut into two parts by a high shaft. In the years 2003-2005 a thorough modernization of the park was carried out, which cost PLN 7 million. Its authors, Marek Szeniawski and Wojciech Trzópek relied on the assumptions of the original project. As part of the modernization, Childrens play area of over 2 thousand. Sq.m. In the corner of the streets of Mickiewicza and Mieroslawski, a corner for lovers with an antique nook was created. The fountain was also restored, and two stones commemorating the 5th and 75th Anniversary of Independence.</string>
    <string name="city03">Arena - Multifunctional sports stadium located on the alley of Prince Jozef Poniatowski 1, built in the years 2008 to 2011 in the shadow of the former Stadium of the Decade before the UEFA EURO 2012 European Championship and officially opened on 29 January 2012. It has 4 (highest) category in the UEFA classification. There are 58,500 seats (all seated) on the two-storey stands, including 4600 seats of higher standard and 69 seats (for 800 people). The facility was designed by the consortium of JSK Architekci Sp. Gerkan, Marg und Partner International GmbH, in collaboration with Schlaich Bergermann and Partner GmbH, responsible for engineering. The official stadium operator, the State Treasury company PL.2012, is responsible for preparing the management instruments for the sports and business complex and for the management of the premises and development of the areas adjacent to the Sports Center, as well as to provide revenue to cover costs, as well as promoting the National Stadium brand and commercialization of marketing and advertising rights. + (From 1 January 2013), created by the Minister of Sport and Tourism.</string>
    <string name="city04">Metro - The only underground railway system in Poland, consisting of two lines: M1 and M2. The first section of the M1 line, which connects the center of Warsaw to its northern and southern districts, was opened in 1995. The full length of the line was reached only in 2008. Construction of the M2 line linking the left and right bank of the capital started in 2010, and its first segment was completed in 2015. The underground railway system in Warsaw is managed by a municipal company, Metro Warszawskie. The company has won numerous international awards over the years. Main awards in the categories Best maintenance program and special prize for environmental protection in the international Metro Awards 2009 and the main prize in the category Best metro in the international Metro Awards 2011. The Warsaw metro system constantly holds very high ratings among its passengers; A survey conducted in September 2014 showed that 98% of respondents rated this transport system as good or very good.</string>

    <string name="history01">Lesson 1 - The outbreak of World War I activated the Warsaw society. Already on August 3, 1914, the Civic Committee was established, with the consent of the Russians, on November 10, 1914, transformed into the Central Civic Committee (CKN), which, as the Germans approached the capital, took over more and more municipality and government agencies. The Civic Committee was of great importance to Warsaw, apart from administrative matters, with the care of the civilian population - for this purpose separate departments were established: the Food, Medicare, Financial, Women, Work Placement, Legal, Information and Press, and Rescue. August 1, 1915 Russians left Warsaw after a hundred years of presence, destroying bridges and destroying strategic objects. The evacuation by the Russians of industrial plants and the destruction of raw materials by the Russians have worsened the citys economic situation.</string>
    <string name="history02">Lesson 2 - In November 1918, Warsaw was declared the capital of the independent Polish state [14], becoming a central administrative and commercial center. The capital of Warsaw was not reflected in the constitutional records of interwar Poland. The reality of the first years of an independent state (II Rzeczpospolita) was, however, very difficult. The situation worsened wars, hyperinflation and impoverishment of the wider population. Among the hopes, disappointments, political struggles and social protests in the streets of Warsaw were events of national and even European significance. In 1920 the city was struggling with the invasion of Soviet Russia. In the period between 13-26 August 1920, during the Polish-Bolshevik War, the Battle of Warsaw took place on the outskirts of Warsaw and in the surrounding areas. The turning point of the fight was the battle for Radzymin, after which Pilsudskis rebuttal from Wieprza decided to win.</string>
    <string name="history03">Lesson 3 - On 1 September, airplanes bombed Warsaw by German planes; The raids continued until the capitulation of the city. Warsaw was defended by General Valerian Czuma (3 September he was appointed commander of the defense of the capital city) and Gen. Juliusz Rummmil (September 8, commander of the Warsaw Army). From 6 to 7 September 1939 Warsaw left the Chief Commander, evacuation of equipment and ammunition from Warsaws central warehouses and surrounding areas, and personnel from both the main military hospitals and the Corps Area Command. This weakened the very small and defensive potential of Warsaw. Against the chaos of evacuation, Stefan Starzyński stepped out and took no formal rights, took over the full power of civil law and, in order to safeguard public order, established the Citizens Guard. As a Civilian Defense Commissioner of Warsaw, he also set up on 6 September 1939 a volunteer formation of the Warsaw Workers Defense Brigade. 8th September Army Warsaw was set up to defend the city. On September 9th, from the side of Ochota and Rakowiec, there was the attack of the German 4th Panzer Division on Warsaw, under the command of General Reinhardt. The assault on Ochota encountered strong resistance of Polish troops commanded by Col. Marian Porwita (commander of defense section Warsaw-West). Attempting to take the city from the march failed, September 9 at 9:45 am The Germans retreated to the forefront of Warsaw, losing 63 tanks (out of 120).</string>
    <string name="history04">Lesson 4 - On January 17, 1945, the Soviet Army and the First Army occupied the left Warsaw, although the right-wing Prague was occupied on September 14, 1944. Behind them, the pro-Polish authorities moved to a ruined and abandoned city. In mid-1945, 20 million cubic meters of rubble (mostly in the districts of Śródmieście and neighboring Poland) were joined to Warsaw. Mines and unexploded mines. The resolution was adopted on the reconstruction of Warsaw as the capital of Poland. On July 3, 1947, the Legislative Sejm passed a law on the reconstruction of Warsaw, entrusting the coordination of the work of the Supreme Council of the Reconstruction of the Capital City of Warsaw. Warsaw, created November 3, 1947 (Under the leadership of Prime Minister Józef Cyrankiewicz). The population returned massively to Warsaw. In the city were political authorities (KRN and Provisional Government) and party (PPR, PPS, PSL, SD, SL, SP). The fall of apparent political pluralism took place on December 15, 1948, when the PZPR was formed during the Unification Congress at the Warsaw Polytechnic, which in fact confirmed the dominance of communist groups by switching to a monopoly system. Pre-war democratically elected council m.st. Warsaw was replaced by the Warsaw National Council after the partys nomination. The presidents of Warsaw also nominated the party. In 1952 for the first time in the Constitution of the Republic of Poland appeared a record about the capital of Warsaw.</string>

    <string name="art01">Teatr Wielki - For over 170 years, the Polish opera and ballet scene is represented by Teatr Wielki, which today operates under the name of the Grand Theater - National Opera. The history of this scene is intertwined with the history of the opera in Poland, from the seventeenth century to the present day. Here we present an outline of history involved in the history of the Warsaw scene, its rise, fall and rebirth.</string>
    <string name="art02">City Art - Every day in Warsaw there are many unusual events: concerts, performances, vernissages, outdoor events, sports shows. Numerous pubs are waiting to be explored, while those who are hungry for nightly entertainment can spend an unforgettable evening at one of the many clubs.</string>
    <string name="art03">Chopin Monument - In the Royal Baths since 1929 there is a monument to Frederic Chopin, great composer and pianist. During the summer, every Sunday, there are great concerts of classical music taking place in which world-famous pianists take part.</string>
    <string name="art04">Syren - When taking up the subject of Warsaw monuments, you must not forget about the city of Syren. It is a symbol of the capital, a figure from the Warsaw coat of arms. There are many interesting legends about it ... The Warsaw mermaid can be admired in Powiśle (just by the Świętokrzyski Bridge) and in the Old Town Square.</string>

    <string name="food01">Cafe Warsaw - Beauty, elegance, style ... top-level service, delicious cakes and desserts, legendary Florentines, excellent coffee for a walk around Krakowskie Przedmieście. 3 stairs in the entrance (outdoor summer garden).</string>
    <string name="food02">Bistro Warsaw - The traffic and the bustle of the bistro were large, so popular. In addition to many typical suggestions for drinking and eating is the opportunity to buy some interesting bread. Prices typical for this area. Nice service and smiling for regular guests.</string>
    <string name="food03">Stop Cafe - The time has come for a new stop.cafe - a place where there is no chance, on the way - the place where you want to be and rest on the go. The new concept is a more ambitious approach to catering at gas stations. It is the whole philosophy, incorporated in the message of the brand, to combine what is close to what is modern and inspiring, every day and at any time giving energy customers. Its culinary pillars, also permanently linked now in the record: freshness.energia.smak, which became the brands motto. It is finally encountering apparent opposites: familiarity and discovery, speed and quality, time and comfort of time.</string>
    <string name="food04">Outside - Great place to have breakfast with friends! Unusual climate, all decorated with head, which makes it an ideal place to relax. In addition to very good breakfasts, everyone will find something for themselves! Delicious, atmospheric and cheap. I will certainly visit this place once again as soon as I come to Warsaw</string>

</resources>
